<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-12-10T20:37:57+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Antonis Angelakis</title><subtitle>Posting related data stuff.</subtitle><author><name>Antonis Angelakis</name></author><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my data playground!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Welcome-to-my-data-playground/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my data playground!" /><published>2022-11-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-11-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Welcome-to-my-data-playground</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Welcome-to-my-data-playground/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post_images/welcome.png&quot; alt=&quot;no-alignment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So…this is my first blog post and if you read this now, I’m really glad you’re here. This is my data playground and I’m going to talk about data, business intelligence, data science, machine learning, big data and all this cool great stuff everyone talks about. I’m just another person with an opinion, but hopefully i’ll bring some data with me. As this is my first post I’ll tell you just a little about me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-me&quot;&gt;About me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with data and talking for all this kind of stuff, really delights me. I try to be into as much as possible components of data analytics, from data engineering to data visualization, however I really enjoy returning value to the business, enabling data mindsets, help people think of data, share best practices and in general everything that helps people optimize the way they work with data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started content sharing on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antonios-angelakis-249899101/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; and then really liked the idea of creating a blog. I didn’t know which is the best option start, just wanted to communicate my thoughts and express my feelings.
This blog aims to become a place to share my thoughts, my opinion (hopefully it will be always opinion with data), interesting data implementations and of course many many tips. 
It would make happy reaching out to me with some topics and ideas you feel is meaningful to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how&quot;&gt;How&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some good news is that it turns out that starting a blog is much easier than you think. The website is created with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; where you can transform your plain text into static websites and blogs and I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; which hosts it directly from the GitHub repository. Like Github Pages mentions,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just edit, push, and the changes are live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was cool and easy to modify the code, understand the logic behind Jekyll and go live. It also made me to remember and review my HTML skills since my Masters. i suppose it’s the perfect opportinity to get more familiar with SEO, tags, and front end. 
The website &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/angeanto/angeanto.github.io&quot;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt; is public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antonios-angelakis-249899101/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, where I already share content and every post which will be published here. I hope you to like it and keep in touch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antonis&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antonis Angelakis</name></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html">So...this is my first blog post and if you read this now, I’m really glad you’re here.</summary></entry></feed>