<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-01-14T15:51:55+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Antonis Angelakis</title><subtitle>Posting related data stuff.</subtitle><author><name>Antonis Angelakis</name></author><entry><title type="html">Increasing the reputation of Business Intelligence teams within an organization</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Increasing-the-reputation-of-Business-Intelligence-teams-within-an-organization/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Increasing the reputation of Business Intelligence teams within an organization" /><published>2023-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Increasing-the-reputation-of-Business-Intelligence-teams-within-an-organization</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Increasing-the-reputation-of-Business-Intelligence-teams-within-an-organization/">&lt;p&gt;Business intelligence (BI) teams play a crucial role in helping organizations make informed decisions and achieve their goals. However, establishing and maintaining a strong BI team can be challenging. Here are a few basic tips for establishing and increasing the reputation of BI teams within an organization:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;clearly-define-the-teams-mandate-and-responsibilities&quot;&gt;Clearly define the team’s mandate and responsibilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important that the BI team’s mandate and responsibilities are clearly defined and understood by all stakeholders. This will help the team focus on its core objectives and deliver value to the organization. It can play significant role to communicate efficiently the mission of the team within the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post_images/3. bi_reputation/bi_structure-initiative.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post_images/3. bi_reputation/bi_structure-team.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; The BI team’s mandate might be to act as a data hub and support initiatives regardless of teams invloved. Alternatively, it can support specific team(s) because of complex data or lack of analysis skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;build-strong-relationships-with-other-teams&quot;&gt;Build strong relationships with other teams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BI teams often work with a variety of teams within an organization, such as sales, marketing, and operations. Building strong relationships with these teams can help the BI team understand their needs and priorities, and ensure that their work is aligned with the organization’s goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Clearly communicate the value of the business intelligence team’s work: Make sure other teams understand how the insights and data provided by the team can help them achieve their goals and make better decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Foster collaboration: Encourage members of the team to work closely with other teams on projects and initiatives. This will help build trust and understanding between the teams.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be responsive to other teams’ needs: Show that the team is responsive to the needs of other teams by quickly addressing their requests for data and insights.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Share knowledge: Share the knowledge and skills of the team with other teams. This will help other teams become more self-sufficient in using data and insights to support their work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be transparent: Share the team’s process and methodologies to gather, analyze, and present data. This will help other teams understand the context and limitations of the data they are working with.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Encourage feedback: Encourage other teams to give feedback on the work of the BI team. This will help to improve and better serve the needs of the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hold regular meetings: Hold regular meetings between your team and other teams to discuss upcoming projects, share progress and results, and address any concerns or issues.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Show results and celebrate: Share the results and impact of the business intelligence team’s work with the rest of the organization. This will help other teams see the value of the work that the BI team does and how we work together to achieve shared goals.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;foster-a-culture-of-continuous-learning&quot;&gt;Foster a culture of continuous learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BI teams should be committed to staying up-to-date with the latest technologies and best practices. Encouraging team members to attend conferences, workshops, and training sessions can help the team stay at the forefront of the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Encourage cross-training: Encourage members to learn about the work of other teams, and vice versa. This will help build understanding and appreciation for the work of different teams and the skills they bring to the table.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Create opportunities for learning: Set up regular training sessions, workshops or seminars where BI staff can share their expertise with other teams, or where other teams can share their knowledge with them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Create a mentorship program: Set up a mentorship program where the BI team can mentor less experienced members of other teams, and vice versa. This will help build trust and understanding between team members.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Encourage experimentation: Encourage the team to experiment with new technologies, techniques, and methods. This will help everyone learn and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Share best practices: Share best practices and lessons learned either between team members or other teams. This will help everyone learn from the successes and failures of others.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Create a learning culture: Create a culture of continuous learning by encouraging everyone to take initiative and take ownership of their own learning.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make use of modern learning technologies: Encourage the use of online resources and digital learning platforms to access training, tutorials and other educational materials.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Celebrate success: Recognize and celebrate the successes of both BI and other teams and how they have grown and developed through learning. Retro sessions are a great way to measure the progress.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use data to drive learning: Encourage the use of data and analytics to measure the effectiveness of learning and training programs, and use this information to guide future learning initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lead by example: Lead by example and demonstrate the importance of continuous learning and professional development in your own work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deliver-value&quot;&gt;Deliver value&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most effective way to increase the reputation of a BI team is to consistently deliver value to the organization. This means providing insights and recommendations that drive meaningful business outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lead by example: Lead by example and demonstrate the importance of data-driven decision making and collaboration in your own work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Understand the business: Take the time to understand the business goals, objectives, and strategies of the organization. This will help you to provide insights and data that are directly relevant to the business.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Provide actionable insights: Provide insights and data that are actionable, meaning they can be used to make decisions and take actions that will drive the business forward.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be timely: Provide insights and data in a timely manner, so that they can be used to support decision-making and inform the direction of the business.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Communicate effectively: Communicate the insights and data provided by the BI team in a clear and concise manner, so that they can be easily understood and acted upon by decision-makers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use the right tools: Use the right tools and technologies to collect, analyze, and present data. This will help to deliver insights and data in an efficient and effective manner.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be flexible: Be flexible and responsive to changing business needs and priorities. In this way, you can deliver value to the business in a timely and effective manner.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Measure and report on the results: Measure and report on the results of the BI team’s work in terms of how it has helped the business to achieve its goals and objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Collaborate with other teams: Collaborate with other teams within the organization to understand their data needs and how the business intelligence team can support them to achieve their objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Continuously improve: Continuously improve the business intelligence team’s processes and methods to ensure they are delivering the most value to the business.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; A manufacturing company is experiencing high costs and inefficiencies in their production process. The team can collaborate with stakeholders and recommend: &lt;br /&gt;
• Specific types of equipment or automation that have been proven to reduce downtime, increase production output, and improve efficiency.&lt;br /&gt;
• Implement new scheduling system to reduce inventory and increase efficiency or a new capacity planning system to optimize production schedules.&lt;br /&gt;
• Implement a data-driven approach: The team could recommend implementing a data-driven approach to production, where decision-making is based on data analysis, rather than just experience.&lt;br /&gt;
• Identify key performance indicators such as machine downtime, labor costs, and production output, and track progress against these metrics over time to measure the effectiveness of the implemented changes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antonis Angelakis</name></author><category term="bi" /><summary type="html">Business intelligence (BI) teams play a crucial role in helping organizations make informed decisions and achieve their goals.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Run python scripts and use output tables with Tableau Table Extension</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Run-python-scripts-with-Tableau-Table-Extension/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Run python scripts and use output tables with Tableau Table Extension" /><published>2022-12-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-12-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Run%20python-scripts-with-Tableau-Table-Extension</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Run-python-scripts-with-Tableau-Table-Extension/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose working in a Tableau workbook and need to make some operations that either are impossible with Tableau or a bit hard. You realise that it would be achieved more easily, in a straightforward and readable way by using some Python code. Another case could be to &lt;strong&gt;make some predictions inside the workbook by running a simple scikit-learn model.&lt;/strong&gt; You want the model to run everytime the data is refreshed.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tableau.com/blog/release-data-guide-table-extensions-dynamic-zone-visibility&quot;&gt;Available in Tableau 2022.3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.tableau.com/current/pro/desktop/en-us/td_table_extensions.htm&quot;&gt;Table Extensions&lt;/a&gt; allow you to create new data tables with an analytics extensions script. We can write a custom Python script using TabPy and optionally add one or more input tables. &lt;strong&gt;Using Table Extensions, you can unlock new data and transform, augment, score, or otherwise modify our data using Analytics Extensions like Python, R, and Einstein Discovery.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Table extensions differs from writing code directly as Tableau calculated fields. It unlocks the capability to use a table in the tableau data model as output after some Python processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setup--configuration&quot;&gt;Setup &amp;amp; Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start cooking 🧑‍🍳.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
First, download Python from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tableau Desktop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Next, download &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tableau.com/support/releases&quot;&gt;Tableau Desktop&lt;/a&gt;(&amp;gt;= 2022.3 version). We’ll NOT use Tableau Server for this example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tabpy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://tableau.github.io/TabPy/docs/server-install.html&quot;&gt;TabPy&lt;/a&gt;(the Tableau Python Server) is an Analytics Extension implementation that expands Tableau’s capabilities by allowing users to execute Python scripts and use the output either in a calculated field or as table extension.&lt;br /&gt;
To install TabPy using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt;, run: &lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pip install tabpy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
and to start the server run: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tabpy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The desired output is something like this: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post_images/2.python_tableau/terminal_rounded.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By navigating to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;localhost:9004&lt;/code&gt; ensure that the server is running successfully.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post_images/2.python_tableau/tabpy_server_rounded.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now ready to taste our food 🥄.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-actual-thing&quot;&gt;The Actual Thing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll use the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sample - Superstore&lt;/code&gt; dataset to build 5 clusters with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Quantity&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Discount&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Profit&lt;/code&gt; variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connection&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
By navigating to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Settings and Performance&lt;/code&gt; and selecting &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Manage Analytics Extension Connection&lt;/code&gt; connect with the python server.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post_images/2.python_tableau/connect_rounded.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data pane&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We can now select any of the existing tables from our connections and notice that when a table is dragged into the pane the input table and output table selections appear in the bottom.We also can insert our script.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post_images/2.python_tableau/code_pane_rounded.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The image used above contains code and schema from another example.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our output table is shown as Table extension.In Script, enter your script, select &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Apply&lt;/code&gt; and choose &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Update&lt;/code&gt;. Now and the results will appear in the Output Table tab.
When the code runs, the output table will include any new columns from the returned python dictonary. The new column &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cluster&lt;/code&gt; has been created. 
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post_images/2.python_tableau/preview_rounded.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The script contains the code below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;libraries&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;pandas&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;numpy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;sklearn.preprocessing&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;StandardScaler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;MinMaxScaler&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;sklearn.cluster&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;KMeans&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#Convert tableau imported table to pandas df
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arg1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;DataFrame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;from_dict&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_arg1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#Fit K-Means
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;kmeans&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;KMeans&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n_clusters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random_state&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arg1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&apos;Quantity&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&apos;Discount&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&apos;Profit&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#Get cluster assignment labels
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;labels&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;kmeans&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;labels_&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#Format results as a DataFrame
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;results&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;DataFrame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;labels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#Rename column
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;results&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;rename&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;columns&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&apos;cluster&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inplace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#Join to main dataframe
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;orders_clusters&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;concat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arg1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;results&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;axis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#Return table as dictionary
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;orders_clusters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;to_dict&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;orient&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&apos;list&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clusters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We can now visualize our clusters. In the &lt;strong&gt;Distribution&lt;/strong&gt; worksheet, we can say hello.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post_images/2.python_tableau/barchart_rounded.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt; The &lt;strong&gt;Discount Profit&lt;/strong&gt; scatterplot displays the correlation between 2 out of the 3 independent variables highlighting the colour of each cluster.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post_images/2.python_tableau/corr_rounded.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell…We’ve managed to run python in Tableau Desktop locally and started a TabPy server. We can store data as dataframes from any database. Depending on our desired outcome, we may use tables from existing connections (or not), manipulate this data based on our needs and finally blend with the tables placed in our Tableau Data model. The python script should return a dictionary which will be used as the extended table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.tableau.com/current/prep/en-us/prep_scripts_TabPy.htm&quot;&gt;https://help.tableau.com/current/prep/en-us/prep_scripts_TabPy.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://towardsdatascience.com/tabpy-combining-python-and-tableau-511b10da8175&quot;&gt;https://towardsdatascience.com/tabpy-combining-python-and-tableau-511b10da8175&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tableau.com/blog/release-data-guide-table-extensions-dynamic-zone-visibility&quot;&gt;https://www.tableau.com/blog/release-data-guide-table-extensions-dynamic-zone-visibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.tableau.com/current/pro/desktop/en-us/td_table_extensions.htm&quot;&gt;https://help.tableau.com/current/pro/desktop/en-us/td_table_extensions.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Antonis Angelakis</name></author><category term="tableau" /><category term="python" /><category term="tabpy" /><summary type="html">Run python scripts and use output tables with Tableau Table Extension</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my data playground!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Welcome-to-my-data-playground/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my data playground!" /><published>2022-12-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-12-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Welcome-to-my-data-playground</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Welcome-to-my-data-playground/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post_images/welcome.png&quot; alt=&quot;no-alignment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So…this is my first blog post and if you read this now, I’m really glad you’re here. This is my data playground and I’m going to talk about data, business intelligence, data science, machine learning, big data and all this cool great stuff everyone talks about. I’m just another person with an opinion, but hopefully i’ll defend it with some data. As this is my first post I’ll tell you just a little about me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-me&quot;&gt;About me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with data and talking for all this kind of stuff, really delights me. I try to be into as much as possible components of data analytics, from data engineering to data visualization. I really enjoy returning value to the business, enabling data mindsets, help people think of data, share best practices and in general everything that helps people optimize the way they work with data. We are also organising &lt;a href=&quot;https://usergroups.tableau.com/athensusergroup&quot;&gt;Athens Tableau User Group&lt;/a&gt; meetups with the rest of the team, inviting enthousiastic speakers, having the opportunity to connect with other data rockstars like you either  in person or online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post_images/about_tug_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post_images/about_tug_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;1st in person Athens Tableau User Group Meetup&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started content sharing on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antonios-angelakis-249899101/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; and then really liked the idea of creating a blog. I didn’t know which is the best option to start, the goal was to communicate my thoughts.
This data playground aims to become a place where I can share my thoughts and opinions, interesting implementations and tips.
The idea is to cover topics related with the Business Intelligence stack from a tech perspective and talk about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BI Tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SQL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python/R&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;plus anything that matters when it comes to interact with data such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effective communication&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Storytelling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Business understanding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be nice reaching out to me with any topics and ideas you feel is meaningful to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how&quot;&gt;How&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some good news is that it turns out that starting a blog is much easier than you think. The website is created with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&quot;https://mademistakes.com/work/jekyll-themes/minimal-mistakes/&quot;&gt;minimal mistakes&lt;/a&gt; theme where you can transform your plain text into static websites and blogs. I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; which hosts it directly from the GitHub repository. Like Github Pages mentions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just edit, push, and the changes are live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was cool and easy to modify the code, understand the logic behind Jekyll, setup &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.algolia.com/&quot;&gt;Algolia&lt;/a&gt;, setup &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt; for search, setup Google Analytics, deploy it to Github Pages and finally go live. It also made me to practice HTML and CSS since my Masters. I suppose it’s the perfect opportinity to get more familiar with SEO, tags, and front end in general. 
The website &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/angeanto/angeanto.github.io&quot;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt; is public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antonios-angelakis-249899101/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, where I already share some content. Some of it will be archived here soon. Hope to like it and keep in touch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antonis&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antonis Angelakis</name></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html">So...this is my first blog post and if you read this now, I’m really glad you’re here.</summary></entry></feed>